See you next time.
Hey, you!
Hey, you come back here.
I'm not done talking with you yet.
Mommy, mommy, what are we having for dinner tonight?
Well, what would you like?
Um, um, rice omelet.
Hey, you sure like rice omelets, huh?
Yep.
Then we'll pick up some eggs on the way home, okay?
Okay!
Sorry, I'm home so late.
Hello, is anyone there?
Aunt Roji?
To Robin.
Today...
as you must know is my little girl's birthday so the family is going out for a special dinner
tonight just the three of us we left some bread out on the table so you can eat that for dinner
don't be too greedy with the jam when you're done eating and before we come back i want you to do
the dishes scrub the floors take the laundry inside and go straight to bed as soon as you're
finished with your chores mommy mommy what are we having for dinner tonight well what would you like
um um rice omelet you sure like rice omelets huh yep then we'll pick up some eggs on the way home okay
okay
oh look here comes robin seems she's stopping by to return a book everyone get in place quick
hello professor clover i finished the book you lent me
one two congratulations robin you're amazing robin a real genius we've got a cake for you by the way
robin the doctoral exam you took the other day you passed with a perfect score
from this day forward you are an official archaeologist and since you're one of us
now we can all work on our research together starting today here this proves that you're a scholar
wear it with pride it looks great on you robin we're so proud now listen up you must understand what it
means to be an ohara archaeologist right i'm ready to learn our knowledge in particular comes from the
past and this library known as the tree of knowledge has stood for over 5 000 years collecting countless
documents and literature from every corner of the world this is a treasure for all humanity to share and
nourish for future generations as the world's largest library knowledge is our pride and joy
under the branches of this tree the finest archaeologists from every sea have gathered
with this vast wealth of information at our disposal there is no historical mystery that cannot be solved
are you ready to join us yes sir in that case i look forward to seeing your research take form and
watching all the contributions you will make to the world professor what i'd really like is to find out
what happened in the blank century oh no you can't i strictly forbid it just as i always have huh i don't
get it if we want to solve the mysteries of the world shouldn't we study the poneglyphs to find out
what happened back then what how do you know about all that did you use your powers to peek on us in the
basement i just any attempt to decipher or study the poneglyphs is considered a criminal act by the world
government i see so that's why you don't tell anybody that's why you study them in the basement at
night you were spying on us so how much do you know this is a very serious matter we're dealing with
here explain yourself robin i know it's bad but even if i ask nicely you still wouldn't let me join you
that's why i studied so hard to become an archaeologist because i thought then you would
finally treat me like everyone else i just wanted to learn robin
i know this is hard you've studied with all your heart and deserve to be called a scholar as much as
anyone else here however you're also still a child if word gets out then every one of us could be put
to death harsh as that sounds it's something we're willing to accept since this became the law of
the world 800 years ago countless scholars have lost their lives as many as there are stars in the
sky but we can't stop now and i'll tell you why of all the scholars who ever tried to decipher the
ancient texts we of ohara are the only ones who have met with any success for us there is no turning
back i swear on the tree of knowledge if you ever come close to the basement again you will be
forbidden from entering the library or conducting research with us you understand robin i hate to say
this especially now but she's just like her mom it's only a matter of time before she uncovers that secret
her mother olvia was only captured by marines a few days ago but it's already clear what fate she'll suffer
uh
Ahh!
Wha...
water?
Wa-Water?
Perfect.
Guess I'm still alive after all.
I just wonder if she's okay too.
Anyhow, thank you for your help, but I gotta ask, is there a town or village somewhere
around here?
Mm-hmm.
That's a shame.
I suppose beggars can't be choosers, but a deserted island would've been nice, you know?
You can stare all you want, but ain't nothing gonna happen.
As you can see, I hurt my legs, so I'm staying put, at least for the time being.
After I feel a little better, I'll build a raft or something to get me out of here.
This your first time seeing a giant, Missy?
Yeah.
I'll tell you one thing.
I may be as big as those guys from Elbath, but I sure ain't as mean.
Just as sure as there are warlike giants, there's peaceful ones, too.
Hmm.
I know this is a long shot, but I gotta ask anyway.
When you get home, you think maybe you could, uh, not tell anyone that a giant washed up
on the beach?
Okay, sure.
Well, that was too easy.
Of course you're gonna tell people.
I said I wouldn't.
Yeah, you're telling a fib.
Ain't no way a kid can keep a secret this big.
Don't worry about it.
That's right, I'm not really interested in you.
Derishi?
What does that mean?
It don't mean a darn thing, I'm just laughing.
That's the way you laugh?
You sure are funny, little girl.
You're the funny one.
I gotta admit, all my life people been telling me my laugh is silly.
But you, you're pretty cute when you laugh.
You should do it more often, I say.
Anyhow, I go by the name Saul.
Jaguar de Saul.
If you like.
D?
Yeah, I don't much know what it means.
But from what I hear, everyone in my family has its other middle name.
Anyways, what about you?
My name's Robin.
I see.
Well, truth is, Robin, some guys are chasing me down right now.
So, if someone finds me, I'm in trouble.
I said I wouldn't tell.
Huh?
Good.
Here's another one.
That is mighty kind to you, Robin.
But you go ahead and take this one.
Go ahead.
Look.
Get that out.
Go ahead.
Thanks, guys.
Look ahead.
Take that out.
Yeah.
Say my head.
We'll see you next time.
So wait, you said you don't even remember your mom's face?
No, but I'd like to see her.
And is she an archaeologist by any chance?
Yep, she's traveling in search of the history no one knows about.
Wait a second, what did you say her name was again?
On the next, One Piece, faded mother and daughter.
The mother's name is Olvia.
I'm gonna be king of the pirates!